Junior Java Dev - Full Stack Developer

Edoardo Orta





Personal Data May 17, 1997, Italian edoardo.orta.17@gmail.com +39 3518026936 http://www.edorta.it Asti, Italy Driver license B Available to transfer/move

Hard skills

Object-Oriented Development

Java 11, Eclipse, JEE, Spring e Spring MVC, Hibernate

Front-End

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript

Web Services

RESTful, Apache, Tomcat

Relational Database

MySQL, MariaDB

Methodologies

Agile: scrum; Waterfall

Git Github

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English B2

German C1

What about me?

I've a young, entrepreneurial attitude, I rarely stay back, continuously trying to develop my skills. I learn a lot by visualizing things and experiencing them in first person.

My colleagues told me I am talented at taking care of customers.

What I am doing right now

Since October 2020 I am a first-year student of the Computer Science bachelor at the University of Turin. I study the Java programming language, of which I started an intensive Bootcamp to master it.

I am a techie who would love to work in these sectors:

Al. IoT. EV and robotics.

Secretary and reception

Ophthalmologist centre

December 2019 to April 2021 Centro Oculistico Ortottico Asti C.so alla Vittoria 103, Asti, Italy

Sunstar Hotels

March 2018 to November 2019

Sunstar Hotel Piemont

Via Bausola 3, Isola d'Asti, Italy

Sunstar Hotel Klosters

Boscaweg 7, Klosters-Serneus, Switzerland Under my pressure the company went online for the first time, I oversaw the website realization, rebranding with a new logo made by me.

I was leading the secretary, working in Front and Back Office. I was the doctors' right hand and responsible for sales. We used softwares like File Maker Pro and Shedul.

In less than two years starting as an intern in reception I worked my way up to become the assistant of the director. We used softwares like Fidelio, Sihot and the Office suite.

Working certification

People's safety during fire hazards course

Course about fire risks, I learned how to use a fire extinguisher and a thermic cover to stop a fire or to let the customer follow the escape routes in case I cannot.

Safety of low-middle risks companies

Corse focussed on the risks you can encounter while working in a low-middle risk company.

Education

Bootcamp - Java developer Generation Italy (McKinsey), Milan, Italy

A 12 weeks online course about Object-Oriented programming with a focus on webdevelopment. From back-end to front-end through an empowerment of the softskills.

Bachelor in Computer Science University of Turin, Italy

I am studying Java and the fundamentals of Computer Science.

Bachelor in European Anthropology University of Vienna, Austria

The centrality of the human person and his culture, how it has been developed this way and why. The today's subcultures and globalization. This was an academic path that was not mine.

Classic high school diploma Liceo Classico V. Alfieri, Asti, Italy

An Italian liceo classico is based on the humanistic subjects, going from philosophy to ancient Greek through Latin and history with a strong scientific base.

Other experiences

Tech Assistant Piemont region, Italy

Helping customers with their tech devices (TV, smartphones), installing them, solve tech problems, explaining how to use them directly in the comfort of their homes.

Bartender Stiegl Ambulanz, Vienna, Austria

It was a challenge to work and study at the same time. It was a competitive job, where you are put under pressure.

IRC - Volunteering Italian Red Cross

Since I was 14 years old, I have learned to work with people with handicap. Other than that, I did a first aid course.

I agree with the General Data Protection Regulation UE n. 2016/679

2019

2019

May 2021 - Sep 2021

Oct 2020 - to Today

Oct 2016 - Feb 2018 -Quitted

Sep 2011 - Jun 2016

Jul 2020 to today

Nov 2016 - Sep 2017

Feb 2012 - Nov 2016

Doors Ora

www.edorta.it/cv/cvEn.html 1/1